Gershon Fiedler

Professional Web Application Developer

Scottsdale, AZ 85254 gffilm@gmail.com (224) 392-2996

ABOUT ME

I am a professional web application developer, and multimedia expert. I have 5+ years experience in application development and multimedia. I enjoy working on a range of projects both frontend and backend and I am always eager to learn new frameworks and languages to broaden my skills.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Client-Server based applications developed using Javascript, HTML, CSS, PHP, ASP, Visual Basic
- JSON configured applications
- Custom MVC design
- RESTful API implementation and creation
- Object Oriented Design patterns
- Designer's eye for strong front-end GUI development and user experience
- Strong Analytical and communication skills

EXPERIENCE

Web Application Developer NYSE / ICE – Phoenix, AZ January 2015 to Present

Key Responsibilities

- Develop, and enhance interactive frontend content player with the following attributes:
 - OOP Modular and extendable Javascript using a Google Closure framework
 - Complies with Scorm/AICC standards for LMS integration
 - Dust Compilation Service (DustJS) for HTML/CSS templating
 - Localization
 - Accessibility

- Customized Google analytics
- AJAX, with fallback to iFrame cross domain communication
- Cross browser support (IE7+, FF, Chrome, iOS, Android)
- Develop, and enhance custom course packaging application
 - OOP PHP using Codelgnitor as a framework
 - MYSQL
 - Advanced form validation using AJAX, with configurable data model to control requirements
 - Custom Analytics using canvas graphs
 - User management using best practices for registration and validation
- Maintain and debug legacy products
 - Update legacy products to keep up with new browsers
 - Resolve XSS security issues
 - TDD

Junior Web Application Developer Corpedia, an NYSE Euronext Company - Phoenix, AZ January 2013 to December 2014

Key Responsibilities

See above for NYSE / ICE. Same responsibilities and company, different brand and promoted title.

Flash Designer Corpedia, an NYSE Euronext Company - Phoenix, AZ April 2011 to December 2012

Key Responsibilities

- Designed interactive instructional content (Flash, AcrionScript 2)
- Web development (HTML / CSS / Javascript)
- Single Page Web Application Development

Designer / Producer / Editor
Comcast Network - Elmhurst, IL - 2005 to 2010

Key Responsibilities

- Designed, edited and animated interactive instructional videos
- Entertainment / Magazine style segments, Spots, PSAs
- Print Designs Brochures, Truck Wrap, News/Magazine Advertising

- Motion Graphic Designs of Cross Channel Spots, Show Opens, Animated Sports Graphics
- Web Design PSD mockups of front end and back end site

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Film Columbia College Chicago 2002 to 2004

Fine Arts
UIC, School of Art & Design
2000 to 2002

WORKING TOOLS

FRAMEWORK / API EXPERIENCE

- Fisheye Code Review
- Mercurial HG, Subversion, GIT
- Jenkins
- Agile
- Scrum
- Redmine
- ServiceNow
- Axosoft Ontime
- Project Insight

- Kaltura
- jQuery / jQueryUI
- Modernizr
- Flowplayer
- Prototype
- DustJS
- CanvasJs
- AJAX
- Google Closure
- Code Ignitor

REFERENCES

Noel Estep

Previous Manager at Corpedia / NYSE (480) 227-8597

Fred Prigge

Manager at Comcast Cable prigs1@aol.com